Harunori Miyagi

Mapleton, UT 84664 | 385-497-3481 | Harunori.Miyaqi@qmail.com |

Professional Summary

Experienced ESL instructor in higher education finding success in preparing students for college instruction

Excels in fast-paced, mission-driven organizations

ESL Instructional Skills: Adult Learning Expert | Transformational learning | Asynchronous/Synchronous Learning | General Service List Instruction | Academic Word List Instruction

ESL Courses Taught: Academic Writing | College Preparation | TOEFL/TOEIC/IELTS preparation | Oral Presentations | Cross Cultural Communication | North American Studies | Academic Literacy | Note-Taking/Lecture Listening

Computer Skills: Canvas/Moodle/Blackboard | Online ESL instruction | Microsoft Office | G-Suite | Adobe CC

Language Proficiency: English | Japanese | Arabic

Professional Experience

ESL Adjunct Instructor 2020—Present

Salt Lake Community College, Salt Lake City, Utah

Academic reading and writing –College Readiness

Instructor 2018—2019

Landmark High School, Spanish Fork, Utah

- Secondary Math and Personal Finance instruction for college preparation.
- 20% ACT score improvement.

ESL Director 2014—2017

Soka University, Hachioji, Tokyo, Japan

- Developed intensive ESL curriculum, 100% success for 3 years.
- Spear-headed efficient academic literacy and college preparation instruction.
- 100% student satisfaction rate on student evaluations.
- 95% student pass rate with TOEFL iBT 80 in one year.

ESL Instructor 2009—2014

Kansai Gaidai University, Hirakata, Osaka, Japan

- Instructed first year ESL for college academic success.
- 99% student evaluation for 5 straight years. 100% student pass rate.
- 100% past rate for TOEIC Listening and Reading.

ESL Adjunct Instructor

Utah State University, Logan, Utah Utah Valley State College, Orem, Utah Snow College, Ephraim, Utah

Education

Doctorate of Philosophy in Education (English as a Second Language), Capella University, Minneapolis, MN2012Master of Arts (Second Language Teaching), Utah State University, Logan, UT2005Bachelor of Arts in Near Eastern Studies (Arabic), Brigham Young University, Provo, UT1999